<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life Motivation Central</title>
    <description>I will take you to where you want to go! Go after your dreams!</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 19:50:06 +0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 19:50:06 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Les Ambassadeurs, the first Restaurant we Visited in Paris</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Within the Hôtel de Crillon, which was built in 1758, Les Ambassadeurs operated as a restaurant since the mid-19th century. It reached its peak of fame as a restaurant and nightclub (a café-concert) in the last three decades of the 19th century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always a center of entertainment for the aristocracy, in the 1870s it also became a regular destination of some of the best known figures of art and the demi-monde. Edgar Degas and Henri de Toulouse-Lautrec portrayed visitors at the night club, and Aristide Bruant performed there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It was decorated in an 18th-century rococo style, redesigned by Sybille de Margérie with furnishings by Sonia Rykiel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following a renovation of the hotel in 1981–85, the restaurant occupied a former private ballroom with windows looking out on the Place de la Concorde, a few hundred meters from the Palais Garnier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Les Ambassadeurs had two Michelin stars. In the last decade of its operation, chef was Dominique Bouchet  followed by Jean-François Piège and finally when the hotel closed in 2013 for an extended renovation, Christopher Hache.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2017 Hache opened a smaller restaurant, L’Écrin, within the renovated hotel; the former space of Les Ambassadeurs became a bar.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>/les-ambassadeurs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/les-ambassadeurs/</guid>
        
        <category>France</category>
        
        
        <category>Lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>One day we just started our adventure</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The die cut has also been employed in the non-juvenile sphere as well, a recent example being Jonathan Safran Foer’s ambitious Tree of Codes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for this particular rendition of Charles Perrault’s classic tale, the text and design is by Lydia Very (1823-1901), sister of Transcendentalist poet Jones Very. The gruesome ending of the original - which sees Little Red Riding Hood being gobbled up as well as her grandmother - is avoided here, the gore giving way to the less bloody aims of the morality tale, and the lesson that one should not disobey one’s mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It would seem the claim could also extend to die cut books in general, as we can’t find anything sooner, but do let us know in the comments if you have further light to shed on this! Such books are, of course, still popular in children’s publishing today, though the die cutting is not now limited to mere outlines, as evidenced in a beautiful 2014 version of the same Little Red Riding Hood story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format, at least in the United States, is thought to be this 1863 edition of Red Riding Hood, cut into the shape of the protagonist herself with the troublesome wolf curled at her feet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Produced by the Boston-based publisher Louis Prang, this is the first in their “Doll Series”, a set of five “die-cut” books, known also as shape books — the other titles being Robinson Crusoe, Goody Two-Shoes (also written by Red Riding Hood author Lydia Very), Cinderella, and King Winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An 1868 Prang catalogue would later claim that such “books in the shape of a regular paper Doll… originated with us”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>/one-day-just-started-adventure/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/one-day-just-started-adventure/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Memoirs supports external images as featured</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Adding images is a very annoying task, I know that, but “Memoirs” theme has external featured images integrated so your publishing task becomes easier now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Education must also train one for quick, resolute and effective thinking. To think incisively and to think for one’s self is very difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We are prone to let our mental life become invaded by legions of half truths, prejudices, and propaganda. At this point, I often wonder whether or not education is fulfilling its purpose. A great majority of the so-called educated people do not think logically and scientifically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the press, the classroom, the platform, and the pulpit in many instances do not give us objective and unbiased truths. To save man from the morass of propaganda, in my opinion, is one of the chief aims of education. Education must enable one to sift and weigh evidence, to discern the true from the false, the real from the unreal, and the facts from the fiction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The function of education, therefore, is to teach one to think intensively and to think critically. But education which stops with efficiency may prove the greatest menace to society. The most dangerous criminal may be the man gifted with reason, but with no morals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The late Eugene Talmadge, in my opinion, possessed one of the better minds of Georgia, or even America. Moreover, he wore the Phi Beta Kappa key. By all measuring rods, Mr. Talmadge could think critically and intensively; yet he contends that I am an inferior being. Are those the types of men we call educated?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We must remember that intelligence is not enough. Intelligence plus character–that is the goal of true education. The complete education gives one not only power of concentration, but worthy objectives upon which to concentrate. The broad education will, therefore, transmit to one not only the accumulated knowledge of the race but also the accumulated experience of social living.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>/external-featured-image/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/external-featured-image/</guid>
        
        <category>France</category>
        
        
        <category>Lifestyle</category>
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>That day when we almost missed our flight</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format, at least in the United States, is thought to be this 1863 edition of Red Riding Hood, cut into the shape of the protagonist herself with the troublesome wolf curled at her feet. Produced by the Boston-based publisher Louis Prang, this is the first in their “Doll Series”, a set of five “die-cut” books, known also as shape books — the other titles being Robinson Crusoe, Goody Two-Shoes (also written by Red Riding Hood author Lydia Very), Cinderella, and King Winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An 1868 Prang catalogue would later claim that such “books in the shape of a regular paper Doll… originated with us”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It would seem the claim could also extend to die cut books in general, as we can’t find anything sooner, but do let us know in the comments if you have further light to shed on this! Such books are, of course, still popular in children’s publishing today, though the die cutting is not now limited to mere outlines, as evidenced in a beautiful 2014 version of the same Little Red Riding Hood story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The die cut has also been employed in the non-juvenile sphere as well, a recent example being Jonathan Safran Foer’s ambitious Tree of Codes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for this particular rendition of Charles Perrault’s classic tale, the text and design is by Lydia Very (1823-1901), sister of Transcendentalist poet Jones Very. The gruesome ending of the original - which sees Little Red Riding Hood being gobbled up as well as her grandmother - is avoided here, the gore giving way to the less bloody aims of the morality tale, and the lesson that one should not disobey one’s mother.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>/that-day-we-almost-missed-flight/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/that-day-we-almost-missed-flight/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
        <category>Lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Observer - National Gallery of Art, Washington, United States</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The National Gallery of Art, and its attached Sculpture Garden, is a national art museum in Washington, D.C., located on the National Mall, between 3rd and 9th Streets, at Constitution Avenue NW. Open to the public and free of charge, the museum was privately established in 1937 for the American people by a joint resolution of the United States Congress. Andrew W. Mellon donated a substantial art collection and funds for construction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The core collection includes major works of art donated by Paul Mellon, Ailsa Mellon Bruce, Lessing J. Rosenwald, Samuel Henry Kress, Rush Harrison Kress, Peter Arrell Browne Widener, Joseph E. Widener, and Chester Dale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gallery’s collection of paintings, drawings, prints, photographs, sculpture, medals, and decorative arts traces the development of Western Art from the Middle Ages to the present, including the only painting by Leonardo da Vinci in the Americas and the largest mobile created by Alexander Calder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gallery’s campus includes the original neoclassical West Building designed by John Russell Pope, which is linked underground to the modern East Building, designed by I. M. Pei, and the 6.1-acre (25,000 m2) Sculpture Garden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gallery often presents temporary special exhibitions spanning the world and the history of art. It is one of the largest museums in North America.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>/the-observer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/the-observer/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title> Culinary Arts in Europe by Jean Anthelme Brillat-Savarin</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The origins of culinary began with primitive humans roughly 2 million years ago. There are various theories as to how early humans used fire to cook meat. According to anthropologist Richard Wrangham, author of Catching Fire: How Cooking Made Us Human, primitive humans simply tossed a raw hunk of meat into the flames and watched it sizzle. Another theory claims humans may first have savoured roasted meat by chance when the flesh of a beast killed in a forest fire was found to be more appetizing and easier to chew and digest than the conventional raw meat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Culinary techniques improved with the introduction of earthenware and stoneware, the domestication of livestock, and advancements in agriculture. In early civilizations, the primary employers of professional chefs were kings, aristocrats, or priests. The divide between professional chefs cooking for the wealthy and peasants cooking for their families engendered the development of many cuisines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great deal of the study of Culinary Arts in Europe was organized by Jean Anthelme Brillat-Savarin, a man famous for his quote “Tell me what you eat, and I will tell you what you are,” which has since been mistranslated and oversimplified into “You are what you eat.” Other people helped to parse out the different parts of food science and gastronomy. Over time, increasingly deeper and more detailed studies into foods and the Culinary Arts has led to a greater wealth of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Asia, a similar path led to a separate study of the Culinary Arts, which later essentially merged with the Western counterpart. In the modern international marketplace, there is no longer a distinct divide between Western and Eastern foods. Culinary Arts students today, generally speaking, are introduced to the different cuisines of many different cultures from around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Culinary Arts, in the Western world, as a craft and later as a field of study, began to evolve at the end of the Renaissance period. Prior to this, chefs worked in castles, cooking for kings and queens, as well as their families, guests, and other workers of the castle. As Monarchical rule became phased out as a modality, the chefs took their craft to inns and hotels. From here, the craft evolved into a field of study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before cooking institutions, professional cooks were mentors for individual students who apprenticed under them. In 1879, the first cooking school was founded in the United States: the Boston Cooking School. This school standardized cooking practices and recipes, and laid the groundwork for the culinary arts schools that would follow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>/press-and-education/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/press-and-education/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
